Name:

Flavio Colonna Romano

Education:

2012 - 2015 Computer science 109/110.

Alma Mater Studiorum, Bolonia, Italy

Technical:

Front-end experience:

JavaScript: object-oriented patterns and related technologies: DOM, Ajax and JSON.

HTML/CSS: HTML5/CSS3, design responsive layouts with css animations and use of the newest HTML5 tags and api;

Css. high knowledge of Less and Sass as css preprocessors.

Javascript frameworks and libraries: jQuery, jQuery Mobile; good knowledge of React.js and really good knowledge and passion for Angular.js.

Flow management. Redux.

JQUERY libraries: basic knowledge of jquery ui.

React.js: good knowledge about the script structure, state and properties, and interaction between different scripts.

Angular.js: really good knowledge about directives, modules and controllers that allow to create single-page applications as React.js.

User experience: good knowledge about the UX principles to apply while coding for the front- end.

Front-end ui frameworks: Bootstrap to build a responsive site with default layout and design;

Mobile technologies: good knowledge about Phonegap, Cordova and Ionic to create mobile apps with web technologies. React Native combined with Realm.io and Redux.

Agile methodologies: I keep track of issues and code changes using Jira and Phabricator in order to organize better the workflow. Able to work in Scrum organized teams.

Task automatization: I use often Gulp in order to make easier and faster the developing process thanks to the automatization of some processes like Minify and Uglify javascript codes, optimization of images and minification of json files.

Testing frameworks: I use as testing framework Jasmine supported by Karma for Unit testing and Protractor for End to End testing while developing wih Angular.

Back-end experience:

PHP: Good knowledge of the language related to syntax, interaction with databases, streams.

Databases: Good knowledge of MySql.

Python: Good knowledge of the language related to syntax and streams.

Node js: Good knowledge of the architecture and routing and RestApi. Using with Express Js and Seguelize.

Web and related technologies: Good knowledge of HTTP elements.

Tools: Git, MySqlWorkbench, LAMPP/XAMP, Gimp, Jira, Phabricator, Jenkins, Kanbanize.

Language skills: I have an english language certificate by Trinity College with a B2 level in both writing and reading.

I have also a DELE certificate by Cervantes about the Spanish language. The level is A2 in both reading and writing.

Summary

Front-end developer building scalable and maintainable applications in the web environment with the latest Javascript frameworks such as React and Angular.

Coding with the latest technologies for the Front-end such as CSS3 and HTML5 api.

I am really focused on the UX, due to I think the first step of coding is understand the user and implement the best UI for them. I have been studying for 6 months in Denmark UX/UI, understanding all the steps to analyze personas and how to test the interfaces.

In the companies where I work I always want to bring my ideas and the latest articles I read.

The companies where I worked, are involved in three main worlds:

- IoT:
- Gambling;
- Online food delivery.

I have been working in Kanban and Scrum teams, so I am really used to work following Agile development.

As main version control I have been using Git in a Bitbucket environmente and Gitlab.

Now I am very focused on the study of functional programming as well as stateless approach.

I am always opened for new challenges because learning never stops.

When is needed I am ready to code also for the back-end side.

Actually I am working at Nexiona, a company that deals with IoT systems.

I am looking for a Front-end position that can offer me a collaboration with a great team, full of enthusiasm and ready for any challenge.

Employment Summary:

March 2017 - Present Nexiona Connectocrats S.L.

A Barcelona based company involved in IoT creating a new solution in order to manage any kind of IoT device.

We are a team of almost eight people, between backend and frontend, working on a Kanban system. As kanban virtual board, we use kanbanize.

I am dealing with create new UIs for the device manager and for all the IoT devices.

Our frontend tech stack is composed by ExtJs, React, NPM and Grunt. Our programming approach is based on stateless components, in order to build a powerful and stable system for our customers.

January 2016 - March 2017 Geneity Ltd

A huge London based company that deals with the sports betting world. This one is a Playtech company and there are around one hundred employees. I am in the Front-end team, with other 15 developers about.

We always use Agile development through great software as Jyra and Phabricator.

Actually we use pure Javascript and jQuery as Javascript side. We use Sass as css preprocessor and HTML5 latest tags to make the code easier to read and meaningful. Our HTML code is played through Python that I use often.

My goal is deliver new solutions as soon as possible for bugs or anything the customers wants. We work on a custom CMS and we try to apply new features on top of it.

I discuss always with the UX department and with the lead of the front-end team to have the best solutions for our clients. Make the code shorter and more readable from the other developers are my first goals.

March 2015 - November 2015 Sgnam S.r.l

- Developing the side of the website deals with food delivery. It is visited by thousands of customers per day with thousands of orders per day. (www.sqnam.it)
- Developing new layouts following the guidelines of UX.
- Restructuring the website with the new HTML5 standards.
- I was in charge developing the all new reserved area with the Angular framework. Great challenge building a reserved area with the method of the single page application. This site of the platform is used by the business team.
- I have almost finished by myself the restaurant manager app built with Ionic.
- Continue developing the reserved area, we choose another framework for different reasons, migrating from Angular to React. Another opportunity to learn another great framework to build web app in the fastest way. My goal was create a platform that does not need in the short future any kind of maintenance. I understood the React framework in just one week, reimplementing the platform.
- The front-end technologies applied, need to interact with the back-end framework, Symfony, through JSON.
 - I am a member of the group that decide the frameworks and in general the technologies to apply.
 - Experience with scrum software to achieve goals in time.
 - Programming with specific code standards of the developers group.
 - Use of jQuery to manipulate DOM faster and jQuery UI to apply different plugins for our needs.
 - Use of latest CSS3 attributes to apply animation and making the code shorter.
 - Coding with Less as css pre-processor used in the reserved area to organize better the css files.
 - Sometimes I develop also for the back-end side of the platform, using php and interacting with MySql database.

Personal:

I am a 23 years old Front-end developer ready always to start a challenge with great dynamism.

I hold a degree in Computer Science at Alma Mater Studiorum with 109/110 as final result. Actually I am a Front-end developer at Nexiona, a Barcelona based company dealing with IoT systems.

In the past I had the opportunity to work at Geneity, a London based company that deals with sports betting world.

My first job was at Sqnam, an online food delivery platform based in Bolonia, Italy.

I knew this great world last year during the Web Development program I attended at Lillebaelt Academy, in Denmark, due to my Erasmus exchange program.

During this time I increased my knowledges about web developing with great enthusiasm and passion.

When I am not work, I dedicate my spare time to read tech news on the Tom's Hardware site, on Medium and on Smashing Magazine site and developing for my own.

I love hybrid apps and the frameworks that allow creating them. Actually I am focused on React Native, building an app for my own.

Now I am involved in applying Redux with React Native using stateless components where is needed. It is a really powerful approach to follow.

In the past I have developed also with Ionic and I published a Ionic plugin in the Ionic plugins market. Checkout the link in 'Other' section to know more.

At the moment I am developing an app by my own with React Native, Redux and Node js server side.

I will publish it soon in the Play Store. Of course I cannot say anymore else.

I really love the mobile world and one day I would like to prove my experience in a front-end mobile developers team.

If you want to know me more please visit my website.

Other:

- Github: github.com/flaviocolonna
- Bitbucket: bitbucket.org/flaviocolonna
- StackOverflow, Tom's hardware
- Interests: football, reading, video games
- Personal website: flaviocolonnaromano.altervista.org
- Ionic Hybrid Apps Plugin Market: http://market.ionic.io/user/71927
- Linkedin: https://uk.linkedin.com/in/flaviocolonnaromano/en